Hello everyone and welcome back
to English Pot. My name is Marco.
My name is Katherine and today we've
got a great informative lesson for you.
That's right. We are going to
talk about an emergency situation.
So what do you do when
you have an emergency?
You dial 911. Exactly.
All right. Well, maybe not in your country,
but today we're talking about
emergencies in America and jobs.
So people who can help you in an emergency.
So before we get into
those words and phrases,
let's take a listen
to today's dialogue.
All right, class.
Now that we're all dressed up,
let's see what professions you chose.
I see a fireman, a police
officer, a medic and a lifeguard.
Can anyone tell me what
these people have in common?
They save people from bad things?
That's right.
Now class, if something bad
happened and you had to get help,
do you know what phone
number you would call?
911.
Yes.
You would pick up the phone and dial 911.
What are some emergency situations
in which you would need to dial 911?
If my grandpa had a heart
attack, if there was an accident,
if the robber broke into the
house, if the fire alarm went off,
I wouldn't call 911 if the fire
alarm went off in my house.
The only time that ever happens
is when we're having spaghetti
for supper and my mom
burns the garlic bread as usual.
All right, we're back.
So now we have a couple
of different jobs for people
that are working specifically
in emergency situations.
So let's take a look at those
now in language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
All right, so we have
a teacher in today's
dialogue who's talking
to her students about jobs.
So probably these students are very young.
And she says another word that means jobs.
What's the word she uses?
Professions.
Professions. That's the plural.
So profession is a job.
Let's say, for example,
a lawyer is a profession.
Or a doctor.
A doctor, a lawyer.
So what's your profession
is another way to ask.
What's your job?
All right.
So they're talking about professions.
And some of the kids
dressed up as different people.
The first one was a fireman.
A fireman.
And so, you know, the first word, fire.
A fireman is a person who puts out a fire.
That means he uses water to stop a fire.
Very good.
So a fireman puts out fires.
Now apart from a fireman,
we also have a police officer.
A police officer.
So an officer is someone who
works in an official capacity.
So in a job.
So we could say he is a
police officer or a policeman
or a police woman.
So three ways to say this.
So officer is for both genders, right?
A man or a woman could be a police officer.
That's right.
So you're going to hear
this very often because
policemen doesn't explain
a woman police officer.
So we use police officer to be general.
Okay.
So we have a fireman,
a police officer, a medic.
Now what is this medic?
A medic is a kind of doctor.
Someone who will look at
your health or help you if you've
hurt yourself, who usually
works on the road, like driving to
an accident or driving to
a fire with police officers.
So these people help police officers
in firemen when there's an emergency.
Okay.
So a medic is not really a doctor.
He's more of a specific person
that can help you if you have
maybe some cuts or
bruises or will help you out.
Right.
So this person will stop your
bleeding or will help take you
to the hospital and
they'll make sure that
you're healthy when
you get to the hospital.
But they are not really
like a doctor where
you work in a hospital
or a doctor's office.
Okay.
And our last profession is a lifeguard.
Well, think about these two words.
We have life and we have guard.
Guard is like protect.
So a person that protects your life.
Hmm.
Interesting.
Well, this is someone who usually
works at the beach or at a pool.
They have a special chair
and usually they have
a cross on their bathing
suit or on their towel.
And this means that they're going to
help protect people who are at the beach.
So if someone can't swim, the lifeguard
will run or swim to get them and save them.
Okay.
Very good.
So you have a lifeguard.
Now, this is for men
and women as well, right?
A lifeguard.
Exactly.
Okay.
So interesting professions.
Why don't we listen to our dialogue again.
And we'll leave shortly.
All right, class.
Now that we're all dressed up,
let's see what professions you chose.
I see a fireman, a police
officer, a medic and a lifeguard.
Can anyone tell me what
these people have in common?
They save people from bad things.
That's right.
Now class, if something bad
happened and you had to get help,
do you know what phone
number you would call?
911.
Yes.
You would pick up the phone and dial 911.
What are some emergency situations
in which you would need to dial 911?
If my grandpa had a heart attack.
If there was an accident.
If a robber broke into the house.
If the fire alarm went off.
I wouldn't call 911 if the fire
alarm went off in my house.
The only time that ever happens
is when we're having spaghetti
for supper and my mom
burns the garlic bread as usual.
All right, we're back.
So now let's start with fluency builder.
Fluency builder.
Our first item in fluency builder
we've already talked about.
The number in America to call
when you have an emergency is 9-1-1.
So we usually
say, "Hey, dial 911.
" Okay, so that's a
verb there to dial.
Exactly.
To dial means to select
the numbers for a phone call.
To telephone someone.
To dial.
So you can dial 911 or
dial my office number.
Or I tried to dial your home
number, but no one answered.
Okay, now you can call 911 for
many different situations or emergency.
One of the kids said, "Well, if
my grandpa had a heart attack.
" Okay, so this is an
example of an emergency.
A heart attack is a medical problem.
It's when your heart cannot receive oxygen.
Okay, so your heart
stops beating sometimes.
That's right.
Sorry.
It's when your heart does not
receive enough blood or oxygen.
So it's when your heart stops beating.
Okay, very good.
So that's a heart attack.
Now another possible emergency
situation is if the fire alarm goes off.
This often happens in
office buildings and schools.
So you hear a T.
Or some kind of strange noise.
Well, that's because there's maybe a
fire or some smoke in your building.
And so usually when
this sounds goes off, it
automatically calls the
police and the fire department.
Okay, now there's an
interesting phrasal verb
that is used along
with this word fire alarm.
We say the fire alarm goes
off or the fire alarm went off.
So that means it started
to sound to emit a sound.
So the verb here, as you said, it's a
phrasal verb is to go off, to go off.
We could say my alarm went off.
Or every morning at seven
o'clock, my alarm goes off.
Okay, that means your
alarm begins to make a sound.
A very annoying sound.
The worst sound ever.
But a lot of things can go off.
We could talk about a bell or an alarm.
Fireworks.
Fireworks go off.
Okay.
And well, the last emergency
that we were talking
about is if a robber
broke into the house.
So if a robber breaks in.
To break into.
This means to enter, to go inside
without permission or without a key.
Legally.
So you don't have to break something,
but usually you break a window or a door.
But this means that someone comes
into your house looking to steal something.
So usually you have to use force.
For example, if I forget my keys inside
my car and I have to break into my own car,
that means maybe I have to force the
door open or maybe break the window.
Yeah, it's not.
Not fun.
I think it usually ends
up being very expensive.
Yes, it does.
All right.
So those are all the
phrases we have for today.
Why don't we listen to our
dialogue for the very last time.
All right, class.
Now that we're all dressed up,
let's see what professions you chose.
I see a fireman, a police
officer, a medic and a lifeguard.
Can anyone tell me what
these people have in common?
They save people from bad things?
That's right.
Now class, if something
bad happened and you had to
get help, do you know what
phone number you would call?
9-1-1.
Yes.
You would pick up the phone and down 9-1-1.
What are some emergency situations
in which you would need to dial 9-1-1?
If my grandpa had a heart attack.
If there was an accident, if a
robber broke into the house.
If the fire alarm went off.
I wouldn't call 9-1-1 of the
fire alarm went off in my house.
The only time that ever happens is
when we're having spaghetti for supper.
And my mom burns the garlic bread as usual.
So, Marco, when you were a kid and
your teacher said what jobs are there,
what professions are there, what profession
would you like, what did you answer?
I always wanted to be a pilot.
Oh, pilots, you wanted to fly airplanes.
Yeah, I wanted to be a jet pilot.
Actually, I collected a books about it.
I read up about it.
So, even till now, I probably
still remember like the
capacity of certain jets or what
types of weapons they have.
I was really, really into it.
Wow, I never knew this about it.
Yeah, what about you?
I could never decide as a kid.
I remember we had to draw pictures.
What I will look like in 20 years.
And everyone had these
pictures, I will be a doctor.
I'll be a veterinarian.
I'll be the president.
I never knew what to draw.
So, you know, I think I copied my friend.
She wanted to be a lawyer.
I thought, okay, that's how I'm okay.
Yeah, I think it's hard.
And usually what you want to be as a kid.
You don't do it when you're older.
I couldn't do it because of my vision.
I didn't have 2020 vision to
actually join me with worse.
Well, and a lot of kids don't know
how many jobs they're all about here.
You know, the big ones.
Doctor, lawyer, fireman, police astronaut.
So, I guess the question for
you is, what's your profession?
Tell us about it, especially if it's one of
the less famous professions out there.
Right.
Because there's a lot that
I don't know about those.
Our website is www.EnglishPod.com.
We hope to see you there.
And until next time.
Bye.